# KRIS RENALDI

South Plainfield, NJ | (732) 593-7798 | krenaldi@comcast.net

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/krenaldi | Portfolio: https://krenaldi.github.io/ | GitHub: https://github.com/krenaldi

### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated Full Stack Developer/Software Engineer with extensive customer service, technical training and management, and project managing experience along with expertise in troubleshooting and network administration and desire to learn new things. Advance knowledge of coding in the following:

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, API, JSON, SQL, SASS

Tools: Git/GitHub, Gulp, NPM, Node.is, MySQL, NoSQL, Heroku, Firebase

Libraries/Frameworks: Bootstrap, Express, REACT, jQuery, MongoDB, Backbone, Knockout

Software: Visual Studio, MS Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Outlook & Visio, Adobe Photoshop & Acrobat

Operating Systems: Windows, MacOS, UNIX, Linux, Cisco

#### PROJECTS

**Common Ground** | Firebase, JavaScript, APIs | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/Common-Grounds Live https://krenaldi.github.io/Common-Grounds

 Incorporated Firebase Authentication for users to login by email and password that stores login information in Firebase Realtime Database.

**MeVite** | MySQL, Node.js, Express, Sequelize | GitHub https://github.com/krenaldi/MeVite Live https://mevite.herokuapp.com/

- Incorporated Passport.js for user registration and authentication by saving user information in a Sequelize database.
- Configured the database to also save event information and contacts for tracking attendance.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AT&T, Piscataway, NJ

VPN Technical Manager, October 2015 - May 2019

Subject matter expert on ordering software and service. Led online training for domestic new hires who were managing the installation and activation of VPN with BVOIP service.

- Exceeded On-Time Performance by having my orders activated and billed before target of 90 days and was consistently a top 5 performer on the team.
- Reduced backlog of 600+ open orders by 80% by having my team follow up with clients as to whether they want service
  or to cancel.

#### MIS/BVOIP Technical Manager, April 2010 - October 2015

Provided in-person training and coaching at overseas office. Developed and updated training documentation and assisted with troubleshooting for MIS and BVOIP ordering.

- Managed and coached a team of anywhere between 6 to 21 people depending on the product I was supporting.
- Slashed end-to-end cycle time for service ordering by several days and reduced number of rejects and defects to almost zero with the overseas team.

## New Hire Trainer / Process Engineer, September 2008 - April 2010

Trained and coached new hire agents for MIS & BVOIP service ordering. Developed new hire training documentation and assisted with the onboarding process for MIS and BVOIP ordering.

• Earned Six Sigma Green Belt and worked with Quality Management team on a Service Delivery Six Sigma Project to streamline the process for a BVOIP product which saved the company an estimated \$823K annually.

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development, Rutgers University, Somerset, NJ, Oct 2019
Bachelor of Arts, Digital Media & Political Science, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Front-End Web Developer, Udacity	2015
Six-Sigma Green Belt	2009
Certified Cisco Network Administrator (CCNA)	2004